

- ☑ sam@gutentag.co
- samgutentag.com
- San Francisco Bay Area, CA

I have grown to find new challenges with Penumbra's REAL™ Immersive System to create Virtual Reality therapy activities to aid in the recovery of Stroke Survivors and other therapeutic indications. From pipeline development to creating performant rigging solutions that give animators creative flexibility in Virtual Reality to working with environment artists to keep high fidelity imagery within frame budgets, I have built upon my experience at Industrial Light & Magic to further my impact and skillset.

I have worked as a Technical Resources Assistant, a Layout and Location Match Mover, an Animator, Motion Capture Technician and Creature Technical Director often concurrently throughout my career at Industrial Light & Magic has given me a unique vantage point in the benefits of an interconnected workflow for a Visual Effect or Game Studio team to succeed.

I am driven by passion for learning new technologies and finding new applications for existing tools, I focus on efficient output and timelines while maintaining an artistic integrity when called for.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

### Penumbra, Inc. - Lead Character Technical Artist

REAL™ Immersive System

Alameda, CA Sep 2018 to Present

- Constructed asset pipeline from scratch for artist workflows to create and author assets and properly ingest them to Unreal Engine
- Led team project in the documentation of in-house tools, python scripts, and commercial software integrations
- Adapted and created several generic, reusable rigging setups for quick iteration of characters and animation adjustments
- Implemented Blueprint Animation state machines and interactivity for VR games and therapeutic activities
- Worked closely with external partners in the development and medical research fields to find creative solutions to existing therapies

#### **INDUSTRIAL LIGHT & MAGIC - Creature Technical Director**

Ready Player One, Black Panther, Star Wars: The Force Awakens, Transformers: The Last Knight, Kong: Skull Island, Warcraft: The Beginning, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Out of the Shadows

San Francisco, CA Nov 2014 to Feb 2018

- Maintained and enhanced existing scripts to suit specific project needs for creature and animation departments
- Led team project in the documentation of in-house tools, python scripts, and commercial software integrations
- Adapted and created several generic, reusable rigging setups for in-house software packages
- Created rigging and asset simulation setups for hero, background, and crowd assets

# **INDUSTRIAL LIGHT & MAGIC - Layout and Location Match Mover**

Bird Box, A Wrinkle in Time, Downsizing Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Out of the Shadows

San Francisco, CA Apr 2015 to Feb 2018

- Convey technical instruction and visual effects task requirements to nontechnical co-workers
- Coordinated data collection used to accurately recreate filmed set locations and for digital set extensions
- Supervised facial motion capture shoots and reference photography for both traditional and virtual reality productions
- Photography of locations, props, and actors used in digital recreations, texturing, scale reference and location spacial diagrams

### **ILMxLAB** - Layout and Location Match Mover

Carne y Arena, Nissan Rogue One Battle Tested

San Francisco, CA Sep 2016 to Jan 2017

- Supervised facial and body motion capture shoots for virtual reality productions
- Virtual Reality Volume calibration for motion capture sessions
- Performed Rigging and Simulation of hero assets for Nissan 3D experience

# **SKILLS**

**TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES:** Maya, Python, Photoshop, ILM Zeno, Vicon Blade, Unreal, C++ **INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE:** Character Rigging, Rigid, Cloth, and Flesh Simulation, Keyframe Animation, Motion Capture, Photography, Photo Modeling, Skinning, Tool Development

#### **EDUCATION**

## **The Ohio State University 2013**

B.A. Computer Information Systems, Animation and Game Development

Columbus, OH Aug 2008 to May 2013

- Course work included Game Animation, Unity Game Development, Motion Capture Processing, Maya Modelling & Simulation, Color Study
- Object Oriented Programming, Python Programming, Database Systems, Data Manipulation